CAPITAL AREA COUNCIL OF CHURCHES RECORDS (APAP129) 1941-2002
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Newsletters, 1948-2003; 3; 0.6
  Relevant topics from the news began to be included in the mid-1950s editions, and radio program and book promotions ended. Announcements of Welcome to clergy joining member congregations are included periodically. Occasionally included are newsletters of other affiliated organizations of those covering topics of interest, such as the NYS Commission Against Discrimination (Fall 1961).
  At some point between April 1978 and February 1982 (series holdings do not include this date range), the newsletter came to be called Connection. Examples from 1982 onward are more numerous and have fewer gaps in coverage than is true of earlier years.
  - Federation of Churches Newsletter, 1948-1953; 1956-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News from the Capital Area Council of Churches, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newsletter, 1967; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Newsletter, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Newsletter, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Connections, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Connections, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Connections, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Connections, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Connections, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Connections, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Connections, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Connections, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Connections, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Connections, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Connections, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Connections, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Connections, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Connections, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Connections, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Connections, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Connections, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Connections, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Newsletters, Other Organizations, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Subject Files, 1953-1989; 4; 3.6
  The file name may be either the administrative unit or function within CACC or the external event or organization with which the materials are primarily concerned. Commonly included records are statements of association with external organizations; agendas for special events; documentation of legal procedures for incorporation of an affiliated organization; prominent events in history and CACC departments and committees. Subject files on associated or affiliated organizations include: Albany Youth Council; regional schools, hospitals and nursing homes; Chapel House; food pantries; Horizon House; Institute for Christian Living; Jail Ministries; NYS Council of Churches; and South Mall Towers.
  Subject files on special events include: Billy Graham Crusade; Russell Broughton arrest; Crop Walk; and the Albany Tricentennial. Subject files on internal committees and departments include: Assemblies; Dept. of Christian Education; Dept. of Christian Living; Faith & Order Department; Leadership Training School; Martin Luther King, Jr. Scholarship Fund and Senior Services. Other subject files include newspaper clippings and photographs.
  - Albany Medical Center, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Albany Youth Council, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Youth Services, Lenten Services, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ann Lee Home, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Assembly, 1980-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Assembly, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bicentennial Celebration, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Billy Graham Crusade, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Breakfast Forums, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Broome County Council of Churches, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Broughton, Russell H. Arrest, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Broughton, Russell H. Case, 1963 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Capital District Psychiatric Center, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Chapel House, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chapel House, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chapel House History, 1966-1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chaplains, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Christians United in Mission, Inc., 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Christians United in Mission, Inc., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Church Women United, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Civil Defense Clergy, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Clergy-Physicians Dinner, 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Clergy-Physicians Dinner, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clinical Pastoral Training, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Community Groups, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Community Thanksgiving Day Service, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Community Worship, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Community Worship, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Community Worship Committee, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Council of Churches Agency, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Crop Cooperative, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Crop Walk, Recruiting, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Crop Walk, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Crop Walk, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Department of Christian Education, Rev. James Richard, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Department of Christian Education, Roy Damonte Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Department of Christian Living, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Department of Christian Living, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Department of Hospitality Ministry, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Department of Hospitality Ministry, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Ecumenical Event, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Ecumenical Relations, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Eden Park Nursing Home, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - ELCA Hudson Mohawk Conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Energy, Nuclear, etc., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Equinox, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Faith and Learning Commission, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Faith and Order, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Faith and Order Department, Thomas Hunter, Chair, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49-50)
  - Family Life, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Family Planning, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Films, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Food Pantries for Capital District, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Gambling, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Giles, Joyce S. Installation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Good Friday, 1982, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Habitat for Humanity, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - HANNYS, Hunger Action Network of New York State, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Holocaust Services, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Holy Week, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Holy Week, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Homeless, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Homeless Shelters, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Horizon House, Minutes, By-laws, Financial Reports, and Correspondence, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Horizon House, Minutes, By-laws, Financial Reports, and Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Horizon House, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Horizon House and Seamans Agency History, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Hospital Chaplains, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hospitality Ministry, Clergy Physicians Dinner, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hospital Work (AMCH) [Albany Medical Center Hospital], 1986 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Housing, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hunger Issues, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Impact, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Inclusive Language Resources, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Inner-City Prior to 1967, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Intensive English Program, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Interdenominational Ministers Association, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Interfaith Community of Schenectady, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Interfaith Experiences, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Interfaith Partnership for the Homeless, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Interfaith Partnership for the Homeless, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Interfaith Social Action Coalition, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - International Club, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Installation Service/Assembly, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Institute for Christian Living, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Institute for Christian Living, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Peter Libassi, Chair, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Robert Hudnut, Chair, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Institute for Christian Living, Robert Hudnut, Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Institutional Ministries, 1981-1985 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Institutional Ministries, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Jail Ministry, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Jail Ministry and Phase Out/Re-Entry (PORE), 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Jail Ministry and Phase Out/Re-Entry, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Jail Ministry, 1982-1989 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Jail Ministry, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Jail Ministry, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Job Fair, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Junior League, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Knickerbocker Lenten Meditations, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Labor Religion Coalition, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Labor Religion Coalition, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Leadership Training School, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Leadership Training School, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Leadership Training School, Rev. Robert Withers, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Legislation, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Literacy Volunteers of America, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Luncheon Forums, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Martin Luther King, Miscellaneous, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Martin Luther King Services, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Martin Luther King Scholarship, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mental Health, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mental Health, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous Brochures, 1940-1976 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mohawk Hudson Foundation, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mohawk Hudson Foundation, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Music Festivals, 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Musical, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Musical Celebrations, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Musical Celebration, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Musical Celebration, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Musical Celebration, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Muslim Christian Relations, Office of, Newsletter, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People Albany Branch, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - New Clergy, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - New York Council of Churches, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - News Clippings, 1960-1962 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - New York State Council of Churches, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Niebuhr Institute Planning Committee, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Nominations for the Corlyle Adams Ecumenical Award-Form for, Undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Organ Donor Workshop, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Peace and Justice, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Peace and Justice, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Peace and Justice, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - People Resources, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 3, Folder 28-29)
  - Prayer and Worship Commission, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Prayer Walk, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Prayer Walk, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Professor Albright Luncheon, 1958 January 7 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Quilt Tricentennial, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Research and Planning, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Retreat Centers, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Retreat Centers, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Schenectady Inner City Ministry, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, News Clippings, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Senior Citizens, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Senior Housing, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Senior Service Center/ Board, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Sexual Violence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Singles Outreach Support, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Social Action Coalition, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Social Education and Action, John W. Jennings, Chair, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Social Justice Center, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Somaltow Housing Co. Inc., 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Somaltow Housing Co. Inc., South Mall Towers, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Song Sheets, Undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - South End Ecumenical Community, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - South Mall Towers, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Spirituality, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Substance Abuse, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Substance Abuse, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Task Force on Advocacy for the Spanish Speaking, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Teresian House, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Texas Faith Friends, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Thanksgiving Worship, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Training Seminar for Program for Peace, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Tricentennial, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Tri-Cities Mass Communications Committee, George Hosler, Chair, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - UNICEF, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - United Nations, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - United Nations, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - University Heights, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Upstate New York Synod ELCA, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Vacation Church School Institute, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Vacation Church School Institute, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, Communications, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Vision Interfaith Satellite Network, Communications, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Women in Ministry, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Youth, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Youth Council, Constitution, 1954-1960 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Meeting Minutes, 1941-1987, 5; 2
  Series 5 includes minutes of the three formative meetings held in 1941 as well as the official documentation of incorporation and topical correspondence. Included in the minutes, or as supplements filed with them, are lists of member churches, size of congregations, financial contributions and indications of existing organizations particular to a single denomination. The names of member congregation's representatives and Council officers are also included with consistency.
  Included is one folder of older meeting minutes (Box 1, Folder 1: 1940, 1942-45) from the Albany City Council of Religious Education, which later came under the auspices of the CACC and Hospital Ministry minutes (Box 2, Folder 18: 1954-61). The remainder of the series are minutes from the monthly meetings of the executive committee and/or board of directors of the Federation/Council. Correspondence is often filed along with the minutes of the meeting at which the letter was discussed. Typically the minutes include a list of attendees; the leader of the opening prayer; the approval of the minutes of the previous meting; report from the president, executive director, treasurer and committee chairs; record of any resolutions or topics of discussion; announcements and a statement of adjournment.
  - Albany City Council of Religious Education, Executive Committee, 1940, 1942-1945 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1941-1944 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1945-1948 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Federation, Minutes, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Hospital Ministry, Minutes and Meetings, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)